Weilin Xu

Intel Corporation 2111 NE 25th Ave JF2-75 Hillsboro, OR 97124 Phone: (434) 326-8676

Email: weilinuva@gmail.com Homepage: https://XuWeilin.org

Research Interest

Adversarial Machine Learning

I'm interested in creating robust machine learning models. My research has developed a generic method for generating adversarial examples using genetic programming, and a general technique named *Feature Squeezing* to harden deep learning models by eliminating unnecessary features.

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science, University of Virginia (UVa)

May 2019

Dissertation: Improving Robustness of Machine Learning Models using Domain Knowledge Advisor: Prof. David Evans, Co-advisor Prof. Yanjun (Jane) Qi

B.E. in Computer Science, Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications (BUPT)

June 2012

Research Experience

Research Scientist, Security and Privacy Research, Intel Labs

2019.7 - present

I conduct research on security and privacy of machine learning in Intel Labs.

Research Assistant, Security Research Group and Machine Learning Group, UVa 2014.5 – 2019.5 I was the lead PhD student of two projects: *Genetic Evasion* which attacks state-of-the-art malware classifiers; and *Feature Squeezing* which detects adversarial examples. Details at https://EvadeMl.org.

Intern Researcher, Baidu X-Lab

2018.5 - 2018.8

I created robust physical adversarial examples against the camera-based perception module of autonomous vehicles.

Engineer, Network and Information Security Lab, Tsinghua University I led a team constructing a nationwide honeynet system.

2012.7 - 2013.8

Student Developer, The Honeynet Project, Google Summer of Code 2012 2012.5 – 2012.8 I created 6Guard, an IPv6 attack detector that was later widely deployed on CNGI-CERNET2.

IPv6 Expert, Nmap Security Scanner, Google Summer of Code 2011

2011.5 - 2011.8

I created the efficient IPv6 host discovery techniques and improved the IPv6 support of Nmap.

Lead Student, Student Innovation Lab, BUPT

2010.4 - 2011.4

I led a team developing an embedded IPv6/IPv4 Dual Stack NAT router based on OpenWrt.

Research Assistant, State Key Lab of Networking and Switching, BUPT

2009.10 - 2010.1

I developed a generic file system encryption feature on the Linux Kernel VFS layer.

Weilin Xu 2

Publications

Reviewed Proceedings

Weilin Xu, Yanjun Qi, David Evans. Automatically Evading Classifiers: A Case Study on PDF Malware Classifiers. In the 23rd Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (**NDSS'16**), San Diego, Feburary 2016. (acceptance rate 15.4%)

Weilin Xu, David Evans, Yanjun Qi. Feature Squeezing: Detecting Adversarial Examples in Deep Neural Networks. In *the* 25th Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (**NDSS'18**), San Diego, Feburary 2018. (acceptance rate 21.5%)

Qixue Xiao, Kang Li, Deyue Zhang, **Weilin Xu**. Security Risks in Deep Learning Implementations. In *IEEE Security and Privacy Workshops (SPW) - Deep Learning Security Workshop (DLS)* 2018.

Micah J Sheller, Brandon Edwards, G Anthony Reina, Jason Martin, Sarthak Pati, Aikaterini Kotrotsou, Mikhail Milchenko, **Weilin Xu**, Daniel Marcus, Rivka R Colen, Spyridon Bakas. Federated Learning in Medicine: Facilitating Multi-institutional Collaborations without Sharing Patient Data. In *Scientific Reports*, 10.1 (2020): 1-12.

Other Publications

Weilin Xu, David Evans, Yanjun Qi. Feature Squeezing Mitigates and Detects Carlini/Wagner Adversarial Examples. *arXiv preprint arXiv:1705.10686* 2017.

Weilin Xu, Andrew Norton, Noah Kim, Yanjun Qi, David Evans. Poster: EvadeML-Zoo: A Benchmarking and Visualization Tool for Adversarial Machine Learning. USENIX Security 2017.

Weilin Xu, Yanjun Qi, David Evans. Poster: Automatically Evading Classifiers. IEEE S&P 2015.

Research Community Service

External reviewer for IEEE S&P (Oakland) 2015, 2017, USENIX Security 2016, ACM AsiaCCS 2016, NDSS 2017, ACM CCS 2017.

PC member for NeurIPS Machine Learning and Computer Security (MLSec) Workshop 2017, ICML Security and Privacy of Machine Learning (SPML) 2019, ACM Workshop on Artificial Intelligence and Security (AISec) 2021.

Invited Talks

Magic Tricks for Self-Driving Cars

08/11/2018: Defcon 2018 - CAAD Village, Las Vegas.

Attack and Defense in Adversarial Machine Learning

09/12/2017: Tsinghua University, Beijing, China.

09/13/2017: Internet Security Conference, Beijing, China.

09/14/2017: Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications, Beijing, China.

09/15/2017: Baidu, Inc., Beijing, China.

09/18/2017: Shanghai Tech University, Shanghai, China.

09/27/2017: SangFor, Inc., Shenzhen, China.

Automatically Evading Classifiers

03/31/2016: Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications, Beijing, China.

Weilin Xu

Teaching Experience

TA, CS6316: Machine Learning, Prof. Yanjun Qi, University of Virginia, Fall 2016. I assisted Prof. Qi in customizing the Tensorflow Playground as an interactive tool for teaching machine learning concepts.

TA, CS4414: Operating Systems, Prof. David Evans, University of Virginia, Fall 2013 and Spring 2014. I assisted Prof. David Evans in developing an undergraduate operating system course (focus on system programming), which is the first course to use the Rust programming language in the world.

References

Professor David Evans, Ph.D. Department of Computer Science, University of Virginia Charlottesville, VA 22904 evans@virginia.edu

Associate Professor Yanjun (Jane) Qi, Ph.D. Department of Computer Science, University of Virginia Charlottesville, VA 22904 yanjun@virginia.edu

Principal Engineer Jason Martin Intel Corporation Hillsboro, OR 97124 jason.martin@intel.com

Last updated: July 24, 2021 https://xuweilin.org/WeilinXu_CV.pdf